sjcsupport.com 2013-12-26

# Help desk and customer support software - Privacy policy Freshdesk

This Privacy Policy is effective as of Oct 10, 2013.

Freshdesk Inc. (“Freshdesk”) is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) applies to those who visit our website [freshdesk.com](http://www.freshdesk.com/) (“Website”), as well as users of our on-demand help desk platform, tools and services offered by Freshdesk (“Service”).

##### Safe Harbor

Freshdesk has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/program_requirements_website_privacy.html) and the [TRUSTed Cloud Program Requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/trusted-cloud/index.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through the website:[freshdesk.com](http://freshdesk.com/) and our Freshdesk platform.

TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@freshdesk.com](mailto:privacy@freshdesk.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here.](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request)  
Freshdesk complies with the U.S. – E.U. and U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Freshdesk  
has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Freshdesk’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>.

Amendments to this policy will be posted to this URL and will be effective when posted. Your continued use of this site following the posting of any amendment, modification, or change shall constitute your acceptance of the amendment. We will notify you and/or the primary Freshdesk Service account holder by email when material changes are made to the privacy policy.

##### Information Related to Data Collected for our Clients

Freshdesk collects information under the direction of its Clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes.

##### Choice

We collect information for our clients, if you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the client that you interact with directly.

##### Service Provider/Onward Transfer

Freshdesk may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to these third parties are covered by the provisions in this Policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our Clients.

##### Access to Data Controlled by our Clients

Freshdesk has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to the Freshdesk’s Client (the data controller). If the Client requests Freshdesk to remove the data, we will respond to their request within 30 business days.

##### Facebook Connect

You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.

##### Information Collected From You

We collect the email addresses of those who communicate with us via email, information about the pages consumers access on the Freshdesk website, and information voluntarily submitted by the consumer (for example, filling out a survey or service registration form). The types of information that may be requested include your name, company name, email address, and telephone number, and credit card information. The information we collect is used to improve the quality of the Freshdesk website and Service, to communicate information about the Freshdesk Service, to provide you with support when you are using our site, to bill your account for services provided, for research, and to contact you about your account when necessary. Your information will never be sold to or shared with other companies or organizations for commercial purposes or as otherwise outlined in the Policy.

##### Communications from the Website

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your email address to send the newsletter to you. If you no longer wish to receive these communications you can opt out by following the instructions contained in the emails you receive or contacting us at [privacy@freshdesk.com](mailto:privacy@freshdesk.com).  
We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email.  
Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account.

##### Service Providers

We use other third parties such as a credit card processing company to bill you for services and an email service provider to send out emails on our behalf. When you sign up for our services, we will share your personal information only as necessary for the third party to provide that service.

##### Legal Disclosure

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required  
by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site.  
In the event Freshdesk goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via [privacy@freshdesk.com](mailto:privacy@freshdesk.com) [prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days] of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

##### Use of Cookies

When you use the Freshdesk website or Service we may store some information on your computer. This information will be in the form of a “cookie” or similar file. Cookies are small pieces of information stored on your hard drive, not on the Freshdesk website. We do not use cookies to spy on you or otherwise invade your privacy. They cannot invade your hard drive and steal information. We use cookies to help you navigate the Freshdesk website and Service as easily as possible, and to remember information about your current session. These are the Session Cookies and they are removed from your system when you close the web browser or turn off the computer. You must enable cookies on your web browser to use the Freshdesk Service.  
Various categories of cookies (including third party cookies) are used in the Freshdesk website and Service. These are listed below along with the options to manage them.

##### » Essential Cookies:

These cookies are essential for the basic functionalities offered by the Service. These class of cookies helps in keeping a user logged in to the Service and remember relevant information when they return to the Service.

##### » Insight Cookies:

These are used for tracking the user activities within the Service, which in turn helps us in improving your user experience

##### » Marketing Cookies:

We also use some marketing cookies provided by third parties to collect and analyze various information about the visitors to the Freshdesk website and users of the service. No personal or intrusive information is collected in this process though.  
You have the choice of accepting or declining the use of cookies through your web browser. For more information on controlling cookie settings in your browser, please refer to the following links :  
More information on "[Incognito" mode and cookie setting in Google Chrome ](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95464?hl=en)  
More information on ["InPrivate" and cookie setting in IE](http://windows.microsoft.com/en-in/windows-vista/what-is-inprivate-browsing)  
More information on ["Private Browsing" and cookie setting in FireFox](http://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/settings-privacy-browsing-history-do-not-track)  
More information on ["Private Browsing" and cookies setting in Safari](http://support.apple.com/kb/ht1677)  
Please note that if you wish to turn off the cookies in your web browser, you might not be able to take advantage of many features of our Service.  
It is your responsibility as a Freshdesk customer, to inform the individuals with whom you interact with the help of the Service about the cookies involved, and obtain their consent, if necessary.

##### Clear Gifs

We employ and our third party advertising partner employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information.

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails recipients have opened. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns.

##### Advertising￼￼￼￼

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by [clicking here](http://preferences.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

##### Security and Storage

The Freshdesk website and Service has industry standard security measures in place  
to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. When you provide us with sensitive information (such as credit card information or login credentials) we will encrypt that information via SSL. While there is no such thing as “perfect security” on the Internet, we will take all reasonable steps to insure the safety of your information. Additionally, you retain all rights of ownership to the data you have stored on the Freshdesk Service. We will not sell or share this data with any third parties or use this data to compete with you or advertise to your clients. Your privacy and the privacy of your clients are of utmost importance to us. If you have questions about our security you can contact us at [privacy@freshdesk.com](mailto:privacy@freshdesk.com).

##### Log Files

Freshdesk collects certain usage and activity information and stores it in our Log files. These information might include time-stamped data pertaining to IP addresses and browsers, internet service provider, entry/exit pages and operating systems. This is strictly utilized in aggregate, for analyzing the trends and usage of various features within the Service.

##### Social Media Features and Features

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our  
site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our  
site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

##### Links to Third Party Sites

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Freshdesk. Please be aware that we, Freshdesk, are not responsible for the privacy practices of  
such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read  
the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site.

Public Forums  
Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [privacy@freshdesk.com](mailto:privacy@freshdesk.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

##### Testimonials

We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you want your testimonial removed please contact us at [privacy@freshdesk.com](mailto:privacy@freshdesk.com).

##### Corrections and Updates

Freshdesk Inc. allows consumers who use the Freshdesk Service or website to update or modify their information by clicking on the My Account link in the Freshdesk navigation menu or by contacting us at [privacy@freshdesk.com](mailto:privacy@freshdesk.com). We will respond to requests for access within 30 days.  
We will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients as well as your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services or services to our Client. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [privacy@freshdesk.com](mailto:privacy@freshdesk.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

##### Contacting Freshdesk Inc.

If you have any questions about this privacy statement or your dealings with the Freshdesk website, you can contact us at [privacy@freshdesk.com](mailto:privacy@freshdesk.com) or via postal mail at Freshdesk, Inc 340 S Lemon Ave #7585 Los Angeles CA 91789.  
￼￼￼￼￼
